Guide to the Whitelaw Reid Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Originals, 1864-1923; Series I
  - Volume IV: Correspondence with Journalists, Divines, College Presidents, Bankers and Financiers, Legal, Medical, Well-Known Americans, American Women
    - Famous American Women
      - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit, Undated [December 27] (Box 8)
      - Sage, Mrs. Russell, 1907 April 25-1913 March 25 (Box 8)
      - Stimson, Julia, 1919 March 3 (Box 8)
  - Volume V: Correspondence with British Royalty, Royal Household, Cabinet, Diplomatists, Navy and Army
    - British Royalty
      - King Edward VII, 1908 December 27-1909 December 10 (Box 9)
      - To King Edward VII, 1909 March 24, November 9 (Box 9)
      - Queen Alexandra, 1910 May 20-1920 December 7 (Box 9)
      - King George V, 1908 July 9-1912 December 22 (Box 9)
      - Queen Mary, 1910 December 24-1912 December 22 (Box 9)
      - Prince of Wales, 1912 jun 23 (Box 9)
      - Princess Mary, 1922 January 26 (Box 9)
      - Louise Margaret, Duchess of Connaught, 1911 May 11, undated (Box 9)
      - Prince Arthur of Connaught, 1908 September 16, undated (Box 9)
      - Princess Margaret, 1909 July 1 (Box 9)
      - Helenna, Princess Christian, 1909 May 1, undated (Box 9)
      - Louise, Duchess of Argyle, 1912 December 16, 1913 MAr 19, undated (Box 9)
      - Duke of Argyle, 1907 November 29, 1910 October 12 (Box 9)
      - Beatrice, Princess Henry of Battenberg, 1912 July 5 (Box 9)
      - (Helen) Duchess of Albany, 1908 June 19, 1912 July 6 (Box 9)
      - Louise, Princess Royal, 1908 June 19, 1909 June 26 (Box 9)
      - Prince Alexander George of Teck, 1907 May 5, 1912 December 19 (Box 9)
      - Prince Francis of Teck, 1907 May 8 (Box 9)
      - Princess Alice of Teck, 1909 July 13 (Box 9)
      - Sophie, Duchess of Sparta, Undated (Box 9)
    - Royal Household
      - Francis, Lord Knollys, 1897 July 8-1908 July, undated (Box 9)
      - To Francis, Lord Knollys, 1908 July 24, August 1 (Box 9)
      - Francis, Lord Knollys, 1908 August 31-1912 September 13 (Box 9)
      - Arthur (?), Lord Stamfordham, 1910 May 12-1912 June 14 (Box 9)
      - Ward, John H., Honorable, 1909 January 10, 18 (Box 9)
      - Frederick, Charles, Sir, 1911 December 1 (Box 9)
      - Knollys, Charlotte, Honorable, 1906 November 29 (Box 9)
    - British Statesmen
      - Asquith, Herbert Henry, Right Honorable, 1910 May 19, July 11 (Box 9)
      - Balfour, Arthur James, Right Honorable, 1899 October 9, 1921 April 29, undated (Box 9)
      - Birrell, Augustine, 1910 May 18 (Box 9)
      - Bryce, James, 1906 July 26-1921 May 12 (Box 9)
      - Campbell-Bannerman, Henry, Sir, 1906 July 16 (Box 9)
      - Chamberlain, J., 1906 May 10 (Box 9)
      - Churchill, Winston, 1908 September 20, December 8 (Box 9)
      - Crewe, 1912 April 23 (Box 9)
      - Cromer, 1906 July 6 (Box 9)
      - Curzon, 1907 May 2-1910 May 19 (Box 9)
      - Dilke, Charles H., Undated (Box 9)
      - Goschen, Undated [July 6] (Box 9)
      - Grey of Falloden, 1905 July 10-1919 November 27 (Box 9)
      - Haldane, 1907 May 19 (Box 9)
      - Lansdowne, 1906 February 14, undated [May 17] (Box 9)
      - Lee, Arthur, of Fareham, 1907 October 10 (Box 9)
      - Long, Walter, 1906 November 23 (Box 9)
      - Lowther, James, 1908 December 31 (Box 9)
      - McKenna, Reginald, 1912 May 1 (Box 9)
      - Milner, 1908 July 8 (Box 9)
      - Morley, 1908 December 3 (Box 9)
      - Reid, Whitlaw (?), 1908 December 5, 1910 May 24 (Box 9)
      - Ferguson, 1905 July 12-1912 May 23 (Box 9)
      - Earl of Roseberry, 1906 February 14, 1908 December 2 (Box 9)
      - Salisbury, 1897 July 14 (Box 9)
      - Spencer, 1905 July 29, August 1 (Box 9)
      - Trevelyan, 1906 May 24, 1912 December 18 (Box 9)
    - Diplomatists
      - Dering, Herbert G., Sir, 1906 June 21 (Box 9)
      - Durand, H. M., Sir, 1907 June 14 (Box 9)
      - Erskine, W., Honorable, Undated (Box 9)
      - Mallet, Louis, Sir, 1906 October 29 (Box 9)
      - Pauncefote, Lord, 1900 April 14 (Box 9)
      - Rice, C. Spring, Sir, 1916 June 1 (Box 9)
      - Rodd, Rennell, Sir, 1906 June 15 (Box 9)
      - Tyrrell, W. G., Sir, 1919 November 25 (Box 9)
      - Vere, Edward Hope, 199 August 2 (Box 9)
    - Navy and Army
      - Baden Powell, R., Lieutenant General Sir, 1911 October 13 (Box 9)
      - Earl of Cavan, Lieutenant General the, Undated [November 19] (Box 9)
      - Duberly, Grey, Captain, 1906 October 24 (Box 9)
      - Fellowes, Reginald, 1906 June 2 (Box 9)
      - Gordon Lennox, Esme, Brigadier General Lord, Indated [June 6] (Box 9)
      - Holford, G. L., Lieutenant Colonel Sir, 1905 June 7 (Box 9)
      - Kelly-Kenny, T., General, Undated [June 12] (Box 9)
      - Kitchner, Field Marshal Earl, Undated [May 9] (Box 9)
      - Wyndham, William, Lieutenant Colonel (to Miss Rogers), Undated (Box 9)
      - Stracey, Henry, Major General, Undated [June 26] (Box 9)
      - Shuttleworth, Frank, Colonel, 1911 June 2 (Box 9)
      - Kitchner, Field Marshal Earl, 1910 May 25 (Box 9)
      - Markham, Clements, Admiral Sir, 1910 June 22 (Box 9)
      - Martin, James Evan B., Major, 1906 June 12 (Box 9)
      - Paget, Arthur H. F., General Sir, 1906 June 8, undated [November 10] (Box 9)
      - Roberts, Field Marshal Earl, 1906 August 6, 1910 May 25 (Box 9)
      - Saunderson, Somerset, Captain, 1911 October 2 (Box 9)
      - Seymour, Albert V. F., Sir, 1911 June 27 (Box 9)
      - Seymour, E. H., Admiral Sir, 1910 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Volume VI: Correspondence: Legal, Peers, sons of Peers, Peeresses, Parliamentary, Divines, Official
    - Legal
      - Alverstone, Lord, 1910 May 23 (Box 10)
      - Kennedy, Lord Justice, 1910 July 19 (Box 10)
      - King, W. L. Mackenzie, Honorable, 1908 April 14 (Box 10)
    - Peers
      - Abercorn, 1911 May 23 (Box 10)
      - Acheson, 1916 June 2 (Box 10)
      - Alington, Undated (Box 10)
      - Ampthill, 1906 November 27 (Box 10)
      - Anglesey, Undated (Box 10)
      - Atholl, 1911 July 4 (Box 10)
      - Bessborough (Viscount Duncannon) [to Miss Reid], 1906 June 26 (Box 10)
      - Brabourne, Undated (Box 10)
      - Brassey, 1912 December 18 (Box 10)
      - Bristol, 1911 August 8 (Box 10)
      - Cadogan, 1910 April 25 (Box 10)
      - Camperdown, 1906 October 15 (Box 10)
      - Carnock (made Peer June 27, 1916; A. Nicolson), 1911 May 29 (Box 10)
      - Chesterfield, 1907 July 21 (Box 10)
      - Churchill, 1907 March 4 (Box 10)
      - Colnbrooke, 1908 December 28, 1912 July 10 (Box 10)
      - Decies, Undated (Box 10)
      - Devonshire, 1919 September 19 (Box 10)
      - Dundonald, 1910 May 17 (Box 10)
      - Durham, 1909 July 21 (Box 10)
      - Eliot, Undated (Box 10)
      - Ehphinstone, Undated [July 12] (Box 10)
      - Esher, 1907 May 11, 1910 December 30 (Box 10)
      - Fairfax, Undated (Box 10)
      - Falconer, Undated (Box 10)
      - Farquhar, Undated [June 23] (Box 10)
      - Fitzmaurice, 1907 March 29 (Box 10)
      - Granard, Undated (Box 10)
      - Grey, 1915 June 17 (Box 10)
      - Grimthorpe, 1906 July 13 (Box 10)
      - Hamilton, F., 1910 December 6, 1911 October 16 (Box 10)
      - Hastings, Undated (Box 10)
      - Howe, 1911 June 25, 1912 July 12 (Box 10)
      - Kilmorley, 1911 jun 30 (Box 10)
      - Kintore, 1907 July 7 (Box 10)
      - Knutsford, 1910 July 31 (Box 10)
      - Leconfield, 1906 July 12 (Box 10)
      - Leigh, 1911 June 3 (Box 10)
      - Lovat, 1908 October 11 (Box 10)
      - Mostyn, 1912 October 12 (Box 10)
      - Mountstephen, 1906 October 10 (Box 10)
      - Newcastle, 1912 December 15 (Box 10)
      - Newry, Undated (Box 10)
      - Norbury, Undated [July 4] (Box 10)
      - Compton (? could be Northampton), 1909 July 18 (Box 10)
      - Northampton, 1912 July 21 (Box 10)
      - Ormathwaite, 1906 May 11 (Box 10)
      - Portland, 1915 May 6 (Box 10)
      - Pajet, A., 1906 June 12 (Box 10)
      - Queensborough, 1921 July 15 (Box 10)
      - Reay, 1906 September 9, November 19 (Box 10)
      - Redesdale, 1906 June 26 (Box 10)
      - Revelstoke, 1906 June 23 (Box 10)
      - Richmond and Gordon, 1906 September 14 (Box 10)
      - Roxburghe, Undated [June 1] (Box 10)
      - Sackville, 1911 September 5 (Box 10)
      - St. Leven, 1912 December 19 (Box 10)
      - Sanderson, 1907 May 31 (Box 10)
      - Sandhurst, Undated (Box 10)
      - Sandwich, 1906 June 30 (Box 10)
      - Shrewsbury & Talbot, Undated [July 21] (Box 10)
      - Somers, Undated (Box 10)
      - Althorpe (Spencer), 1909 May 28 (Box 10)
      - Spencer, 1912 December 19 (Box 10)
      - Stafford, Undated (Box 10)
      - Tweedmouth, 1906 June 2 (Box 10)
      - Vallifort, 1908 July 16 (Box 10)
      - Yarborough, Earl of (signed Worsley), 1908 July 19 (Box 10)
    - Sons of Peers
      - Rocksavage, Undated (Box 10)
      - Lennox, ALgernon, Lord, 1908 June 29 (Box 10)
      - Nevill, Richard, Lord, 1905 June 14 (Box 10)
      - Brett, Oliver, Honorable, Undated (Box 10)
      - Brooke, Lord, 1906 June 23 (Box 10)
      - Dalmey, Lord, 1909 April 6 (Box 10)
    - Peeresses
      - Aberdeen, 1909 May 15 (Box 10)
      - Antrim, L., 1911 April 15 (Box 10)
      - Brougham and Vaux, Undated (Box 10)
      - Castletown, Undated [May 22] (Box 10)
      - Chesleymore, Elizabeth, 1906 July 18 (Box 10)
      - Churchill, Undated (Box 10)
      - Crewe, Margaret, Undated (Box 10)
      - Darthmouth, Mary, Undated [July 11] (Box 10)
      - Dartrey, Julia, 1906 June 9 (Box 10)
      - Desborough, Ethel, Undated [June 13] (Box 10)
      - Devonshire, Evelyn, 1910 jun 4 (Box 10)
      - Donoughmore, 1906 July 12 (Box 10)
      - Dudley, G., 1910 May 26 (Box 10)
      - Dudley, Rachel, Undated (Box 10)
      - Essex, Undated (Box 10)
      - Fitzwilliam, Undated (Box 10)
      - Gosford, Undated (Box 10)
      - Beatrice (annotated Granard), Undated [February 25] (Box 10)
      - Grenfell, Victoria, 1906 July 16 (Box 10)
      - Grey, Alice, 1906 June 13 (Box 10)
      - Hamilton, 1909 October 19 (Box 10)
      - Jersey, M. E., 1906 July 12 (Box 10)
      - Lansdowne, Maud, Undated (Box 10)
      - Leith, Louise, Undated [June 8] (Box 10)
      - Limerick, Isabella, 1906 June 8, undated (Box 10)
      - Lincolnshire (signed Lily Carrington; husband made peer Feb. 26, 1912), Undated [July 4] (Box 10)
      - Londonderry, Undated [May 26] (Box 10)
      - Londesborough, Undated (Box 10)
      - Manners, Constance, Undated [April 21] (Box 10)
      - Mar and Kellie, Violet, Undated (Box 10)
      - Marlborough, Undated (Box 10)
      - Norfolk, C., 1901 May 9 (Box 10)
      - Pembroke, Beatrix, 1906 May 26 (Box 10)
      - Portsmouth, 1905 July 12 (Box 10)
      - Powis, Violet, Undated [February 13] (Box 10)
      - Roxburghe, Mary, Undated (Box 10)
      - Somerset, Susan, Undated [June 1] (Box 10)
      - Wellington, Kathleen, Undated (Box 10)
      - Willoughby de Eresby, 1906 June 6 (Box 10)
      - Wimbourne, Cornelia, 1906 June 20 (Box 10)
      - Wolverton, Edith, 1906 June 13 (Box 10)
      - Yarborough, Undated (Box 10)
    - Parliament
      - Bradlaugh, C., 1873 January 26 (Box 10)
      - Bright, J. A., 1907 November 17 (Box 10)
      - Brittain, Harry, Sir, 1921 May 15 (Box 10)
      - Verney, Frederick, Undated (Box 10)
      - Stanley, Arthur, Honorable Sir (Box 10)
    - Divines
      - Davidson, Randall, Archbishop of Canterbury, 1908 March 14, 1910 May 25 (Box 10)
      - Archbishop of York, 1912 August 19 (Box 10)
      - Bishop of London, 1907 October 17, 1910 May 24 (Box 10)
      - Bishop of Hereford, 1906 September 21 (Box 10)
      - Bishop of Worcester, Undated [October 31] (Box 10)
      - Ryle, Herbert E., Dean of Westminster (to Mr. Ward), 1912 December 27 (Box 10)
      - Sinclair, William, Archdeacon, 1912 December 16, 1914 March 31 (Box 10)
      - Wilberforce, Basil, Archdeacon of Westminster, 1902 July 25 (Box 10)
      - Butler, A. Montagu, 1902 May 31 (Box 10)
      - Lyttelton, Edward, Honorable, 1908 March 16 (Box 10)
    - Official
      - Dawson, Douglas, Sir, 1906 July 12 (Box 10)
      - Earle, Lionel, Sir, 1906 June 8, 12 (Box 10)
      - Edwards, Fleetwood, Sir, 1902 July 3 (Box 10)
      - Garstin, W. E., Sir, 1912 December 15 (Box 10)
      - Greville, Sidney, Honorable Sir, 1906 April 26 (Box 10)
      - Lister-Kaye, John, Sir, Undated [May 12] (Box 10)
      - McDonnell, Schomberg, Sir (to Walsh), 1906 October 1 (Box 10)
      - Thomas, Godfrey, Sir, 1919 September 3 (Box 10)
      - Wallington, Edward, Sir (to Honorable John H. Ward, C.V.O.), 1914 Fev 14 (Box 10)
      - Wallace, Donald, Sir, 1907 May 26, June 29 (Box 10)
      - Parkes, Henry, 1883 June 10 (Box 10)
  - Volume VII: Correspondence with Authors and Journalists, Medical, Artists, Musicians, the Stage, Financiers, Well-Known Women, Foreigners
    - British Authors and Journalists
      - Arnold, Matthew, 1883 October 23 (Box 11)
      - Austin, Alfred, 1906 March 10 (Box 11)
      - Black, William, 1876 October 17 (Box 11)
      - Bodley, J. E. C., 1902 November 27 (Box 11)
      - Collins, Wilkie, 1874 March 6 (Box 11)
      - Crawford, F. Marion, 1883 February 21 (Box 11)
      - Dicey, Edward, 1874 October 23 (Box 11)
      - Doyle, Arthur C., 1909 October 4 (Box 11)
      - Edwards, Amelia B., 1880 April 24 (Box 11)
      - Gosse, Edmund, 1884 December 31 (Box 11)
      - Farjeon, B. J., 1877 November 15 (Box 11)
      - Haggard, H. Rider, 1906 August 28, 1907 August 30 (Box 11)
      - Hughes, Thomas (?) W., 1891 March 31 (Box 11)
      - Kingsley, C., Undated [February 27] (Box 11)
      - Kipling, Rudyard, 1905 October 31 (Box 11)
      - Lee, Sidney, 1911 November 23 (Box 11)
      - Lucy, Henry W., 1888 December 3-1907 June 4 (Box 11)
      - McCarthy, Justin, 1882 May 19 (Box 11)
      - Maxwell, Herbert, 1906 November 6, 1907 October 25 (Box 11)
      - Northcliffe, Lord, 1908 November 18 (Box 11)
      - Reade, Charles, 1875 October 2 (Box 11)
      - Reid, Mayne, 1881 February 28 (Box 11)
      - Russell, G. W. E., 1908 June 25 (Box 11)
      - Sala, George A., 1879 December 19 (Box 11)
      - Shaw, George Bernard, 1912 July 27 (Box 11)
      - Stead, William T., 1908 August 11 (Box 11)
      - Trollope, T. Adolphus, 1881 December 23 (Box 11)
      - Yates, Edmund, Undated (Box 11)
    - Medical
      - Fripp, Alfred, 1909 May 26 (Box 11)
      - Osler, William, 1912 November 20, undated (Box 11)
    - Artists
      - Abbey, Edwin A., 1909 March 24 (Box 11)
      - Bartholdi, A., 1889 June 19 (Box 11)
      - Cain, Auguste, 1893 April 24 (Box 11)
      - French, Daniel C., 1908 December 6 (Box 11)
      - Gallard, F. V., 1892 August 2 (Box 11)
      - Gifford, R. Swain, 1881 April 26 (Box 11)
      - Haden, F. Seymour, 1883 February 13, 1906 September 6 (Box 11)
      - Healey, George P. A., 1890 February 28 (Box 11)
      - Moscheles, Felix, 1884 September 11 (Box 11)
      - Sargent, John Singer, 1907 June 21, Undated [May 26] (Box 11)
      - Tadema, Alma, 1882 February 2, November 2 (Box 11)
      - Ward, J. Q. A., 1888 November 7 (Box 11)
      - Thompson, L., 1870 March 5 (Box 11)
    - Musicians
      - Abbott, Emma, 1881 January 26 (Box 11)
      - Campanini, Italo, 1888 November 15 (Box 11)
      - Gorlitz, Hugo, Undated (Box 11)
      - Kreisler, Fritz, 1902 May 18 (Box 11)
      - Melba, Nellie, Undated (Box 11)
      - Nordica, Lillian, Undated [November 18] (Box 11)
      - Sanderson, Sibyl, 1891 November (Box 11)
    - The Stage
      - Barnum, P. T., 1869 June 8 (Box 11)
      - Beckett, Harry, Undated [September 27] (Box 11)
      - Bernhardt, Sarah, 1880 (Box 11)
      - Booth, Edwin (to Stedman), 1880 June 24 (Box 11)
      - Brougham, John, 1878 October 8 (Box 11)
      - Cushman, Charlotte, 1894 August 14 (Box 11)
      - Daly, Augustin, 1894 September 16 (Box 11)
      - Davenport, Fanny, 1896 October 6 (Box 11)
      - Robertson, Norman Forbes, Circa 1909 [June 19] (Box 11)
      - Irving, Henry, Sir, 1902 June 18 (Box 11)
      - Tree, Herbert B., Sir, 1909 May 24-June 2 (Box 11)
      - Wallack, Lester, 1883 December 10 (Box 11)
      - Wyndham, Charles, Sir, 1906 November 28 (Box 11)
    - Financiers
      - Cassel, Ernest, Sir, 1908 September 24-1909 May 16, undated (Box 11)
      - Rothschild, Alfred de, 1907 May 13, 1911 June 10 (Box 11)
    - Well-Known Women
      - Asquith, Mary (Mrs. H. H.), Undated (Box 11)
      - Cornwallis-West, Mrs. (Lady Randolph Churchill), 1912 June 11 (Box 11)
      - Knill, E., Lady, 1910 May 7 (Box 11)
      - Lister Kaye, Lady, Undated [June 2] (Box 11)
      - Parker, Lady, Undated [June 11] (Box 11)
      - Townley, Susan, Lady, Undated (Box 11)
    - Foreign Authors
      - Aboout, Edmond, 1878 May 8 (Box 11)
      - Anderson, Hans Christian, 1875 April 17 (Box 11)
      - Blowitz, 1891 May (Box 11)
      - Houssaye, Arsene, 1893 January 18 (Box 11)
      - Taine, H., 1890 March 11 (Box 11)
    - Foreigners (Men)
      - D'Alba, Undated (Box 11)
      - Benckendorff, 1907 April 30 (Box 11)
      - Brun, C., 1912 June 3, 25 (Box 11)
      - Cambon, Jules, 1902 October 31, November 23 (Box 11)
      - Cambon, Paul, 1902 July 26, 1907 May 28, undated (Box 11)
      - Carlin, G., 1910 June 7 (Box 11)
      - Li Ching-Fong, 1910 June 9 (Box 11)
      - Covorrubias, M., 1910 June 6 (Box 11)
      - De Gramont, Undated [July 7] (Box 11)
      - Dupuy de Lome, E., 1897 February 20 (Box 11)
      - Deschanel, Paul, 1891 October 17, 1912 December 16 (Box 11)
      - Edwards, L. Justin, 1912 December 20 (Box 11)
      - Galkwar, Chimmabai, Undated (Box 11)
      - Hayashi, Tadasu, 1906 February 19 (Box 11)
      - Holleben, A., Undated [November 30] (Box 11)
      - Imperiali, Undated (Box 11)
      - Jusserand, 1915 July 7 (Box 11)
      - Kato, T., 1912 July 26 (Box 11)
      - Kato, Haru, Baroness, Undated [June 5] (Box 11)
      - Kossuth, L., 1870 August 19 (Box 11)
      - Lasteyrie, 1890 May 3 (Box 11)
      - Mensdorff, Albert, Undated (Box 11)
      - Metternich, P., 1908 December 22 (Box 11)
      - Munster, 1899 April 7 (Box 11)
      - Patenotre, 1892 April 30 (Box 11)
      - Revfik, 1910 June 6 (Box 11)
      - Ribot, 1891 August 9 (Box 11)
      - Rochambeau (to Mr. Harjes), 1892 March 23 (Box 11)
      - San Giuliano, 1906 October 12-1909 October 28 (Box 11)
      - Siegfried, Jules, 1892 March 19 (Box 11)
      - Simon, Jules, 1889 September 8 (Box 11)
      - Soveral, 1910 June 6, undated [July 14] (Box 11)
      - Stumm, 1909 July 29 (Box 11)
      - Szechenyi (to Miss Reid), 1907 July 5 (Box 11)
      - Van Swinderen, R., 1909 March 30 (Box 11)
      - Villa Urrutia, 1906 October 22 (Box 11)
      - Vogt, 1910 June 7 (Box 11)
      - Wrangel, Undated [June 7] (Box 11)
    - Foreigners (Women)
      - Benckendorff, Sophie, Mme., Undated (Box 11)
      - Crommelin, Edith M., Mme., 1910 June 7 (Box 11)
      - Dominguez, Mme. (to Miss Rogers), Undated [June 6] (Box 11)
      - Ellen of Greece, Undated [March 18] (Box 11)
      - Gana, Margarita E. de, Mme., 1910 June 4 (Box 11)
      - Henriette, Duchess of Vendome, Princess of Belgium, 1915 February 1, December 17 (Box 11)
      - Kato, Haru, Baroness, Undated [June 6] (Box 11)
      - Kawananakoa, Abbie, Undated (Box 11)
      - Lalaing, Christine de, 1910, undated [June 13] (Box 11)
      - Lasteyrie, Olivia de, Undated (Box 11)
      - Lichenstein, Irma, 1901 May 31 (Box 11)
      - Oliviera, Amelia R., Undated (Box 11)
      - Teano, Vittoria de, Undated (Box 11)
      - Triana, Gertrude, 1910 June 5 (Box 11)
      - Villa Urrutia, Mme., Undated [June 7] (Box 11)
      - Vidiella, Mme. Federico R., 1910 June 5 (Box 11)
  - Volume VIII: President Roosevelt on the Morocco Question 1906, 1906 April 28-1907 November 14 (Box 12)
  - Volume IX: Mr. Horace Greeley's Famous Letter to Senator Morton of Indiana, on Resumption of Species Payments
    - Photograph of Horace Greeley, Undated (Box 12)
    - Introduction (1 page), 1892 December 7 (Box 12)
    - Bound letter (15 pages), 1868 December 21 (Box 12)
  - Oversized material
    - Dinner program and menu, 1905 (Box 4)
    - Punch, volume xxxii, no. 809, 811, 820, 1892 (Box 4)
- Use copies
  Scope and Contents
  Use copies consist of microfilm (Film HM 169) and copies made from the microfilm.
  - Volume I: Correspondence with Presidents, Vice Presidents, State Governors
    - Presidents (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 1-92)
    - Vice-presidents (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 93-110)
    - State governors (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 111-129)
  - Volume II: Correspondence with Cabinet, Ambassadors, Consuls, Senators
    - Cabinet members and associates (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 130-232)
    - Ambassadors and consuls (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 233-325)
    - Spanish Peace Commission (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 326-333)
    - Senators (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 334-392)
  - Volume III: Correspondence with Congressmen, Judges, Navy and Army, Mayors of New York City, Authors
    - Congressmen (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 393-429)
    - Judges (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 430-458)
    - Navy and Army (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 459-517)
    - Mayors of New York (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 518-523)
    - American authors (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 524-649)
  - Volume IV: Correspondence with Journalists, Divines, College Presidents, Bankers and Financiers, Legal, Medical, Well-Known Americans, American Women
    - American journalists (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 650-722)
    - Divines (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 723-757)
    - College presidents (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 758-809)
    - Bankers, financiers (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 810-848)
    - Legal (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 849-862)
    - Medical (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 863-872)
    - Famous Americans (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 873-913)
    - Famous American women (Box 1, Reel 1, Frame 914-929)
  - Volume V: Correspondence with British Royalty, Royal Household, Cabinet, Diplomatists, Navy and Army
    - British royalty (Box 2, Reel 1, Frame 930-1050)
    - Royal household (Box 2, Reel 1, Frame 1051-1106)
    - British statesmen (Box 2, Reel 1, Frame 1107-1199)
    - Diplomatists (Box 2, Reel 1, Frame 1200-1220)
    - Navy and Army (Box 2, Reel 1, Frame 1221-1256)
  - Volume VI: Correspondence: Legal, Peers, Sons of Peers, Peeresses, Parliamentary, Divines, Official
    - Legal (Box 2, Reel 2, Frame 1257-1262)
    - Peers (Box 2, Reel 2, Frame 1263-1396)
    - Sons of peers (Box 2, Reel 2, Frame 1397-1409)
    - Peeresses (Box 2, Reel 2, Frame 1410-1496)
    - Parliament (Box 2, Reel 2, Frame 1497-1503)
    - Divines (Box 2, Reel 2, Frame 1504-1528)
    - Official (Box 2, Reel 2, Frame 1529-1551)
  - Volume VII: Correspondence with Authors and Journalists, Medical, Artists, Musicians, the Stage, Financiers, Well-Known Women, Foreigners
    - British authors and journalists (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1552-1607)
    - Medical (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1608-1611)
    - Artists (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1612-1643)
    - Musicians (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1644-1658)
    - The stage (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1659-1691)
    - Financiers (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1692-1700)
    - Well-known women (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1701-1712)
    - Foreign authors (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1713-1723)
    - Foreigners (men) (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1724-1803)
    - Foreigners (women) (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1804-1840)
  - Volume VIII: President Roosevelt on the Morocco Question 1906 (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1841-1937)
  - Volume IX: Mr. Horace Greeley's Famous Letter to Senator Morton of Indiana, on Resumption of Specie Payments (Box 3, Reel 2, Frame 1938-end)